地球百子  前情提要
previously on "the 100"...
再也没有战争了  克拉克
no more fighting, clarke.
长眠吧  在更美好的地方  就像你一直想要的那样
be at peace, a better place, just like you said you wanted.
这我倒是挺满意的
now, this i can work with.
你是谁
who are you?
约瑟芬  光明之子  幸会
josephine lightbourne. nice to meet you.
你不是克拉克
you're not clarke.
那个女人是个魔鬼
that woman's a monster.
怎么了  莉莉
what's the matter, lee-lee?
你认不出自己最好的朋友了吗
you don't recognize your best friend?
- 约瑟芬  - 惊喜吧
- josephine? - surprise.
你是我倒下去看见的最后一张脸
yours was the last face i saw before i fell.
现在我们扯平了
now we're even.
贝拉米  出什么事了
bellamy, what's going on?
克拉克死了
clarke's dead.
我爸的死都是你的错
i blame you because my father's dead,
也是我妈的错
and it's my mother's fault.
- 还有谁  - 欢迎回来
- who else? - welcome back.
我再也不需要假装了
i don't have to pretend anymore.
真相让人难受
the truth hurts.
这是能量
this is the energy.
我是个指挥官
i'm a commander.
还要牺牲多少人
how many have to die?
我很抱歉  莱克萨
i'm sorry, lexa.
如果我当时和贝拉米在一起  我永远都不会遇见你
if i was with bellamy, i never would have met you.
319号囚犯  面向墙壁
prisoner 319, face the wall.
他们要带走他们了
they're all taking them.
扎哈
jaha...
爸爸
dad?
你好啊  亲爱的
hello, sweetheart.
这怎么可能呢  我们怎们会在这儿
how is this possible? how are we here?
你最后的记忆是什么
what's the last thing you remember?
我死了
i died.
过来一下  过来
come here a second. come on.
你可以休息一下
now you rest.
全都结束了
it's over.
我奋斗了这么久
i've been fighting for so long.
我明白
i know you have.
我从没想到还能见到你
i never thought i'd see you again.
我都没有机会和他们告别
i didn't get to say good-bye
和麦蒂  和妈妈
to madi, to mom.
什么鬼啊
what the hell?
我每次难过的时候都会下雨
it started when i got upset.
克拉克  仔细听  你听到了什么
clarke, listen. what do you hear?
- 雨声  - 我在认真问你话呢
- rain? - ha! i'm serious.
仔细听  在雨声中
focus. between the raindrops,
你还能听到什么
what else do you hear?
心跳声
a heartbeat.
我还活着
i'm still alive.
不  不
no. no.
我亲眼看到的  他杀了我
i saw it. he killed me.
他没有
didn't.
你只是我脑袋里想出来的
you're just in my head.
我喜欢和麦蒂一起呆在这里
i loved being here with madi,
我爱你  所以你出现在了我脑海里
and i love you, so here you are.
亲爱的
oh, sweetheart...
我不明白  我是在做梦吗
i don't understand. am i dreaming?
这个地方在回应你
this place is reacting to you,
所以我们只是在你的潜意识里
so we're just in your subconscious somehow,
但除了这一点
but beyond that,
这里没有你需要的答案  克拉克
there are no answers for you here, clarke,
所以  去吧
so go on.
去搞清楚这是怎么回事
go figure this out.
如果你需要我  我就在这里
i'll be here if you need me.
我爱你  爸爸
i love you, dad.
永远爱你
forever.
去吧
go on.
地 球 百 子
第六季        第七集
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
翻译： 文睿
翻译： Asteroid
翻译： 岛岛
翻译： RossyGeng
校对： 文睿
时间轴/特效：小螺号
统筹：Kate
总监：麦斯
圣地是我的
sanctum is mine!
这到底是什么回事
what the hell is going on?
它确实在回应我
it is reacting to me.
你好  克拉克
hello, clarke.
不可能
no.
我按下了杀戮开关  我毁掉了你
i pulled the kill switch. i destroyed you.
而我救了你
and i saved you.
不然你觉得你为什么会在这里
why do you think you're still here?
我也许是不在了
i may be gone,
但因为我
but this precious depository
你的珍贵记忆
of your memories is here
全都在这里
because of me.
不用谢
you're welcome.
那些神经网络还在我脑子里
the neural mesh is still in my head.
它肯定干扰了那些
it must have interfered with the drug
除去我记忆的药物
they used to wipe my mind.
没错  所以你也就明白了
correct, and so, you see,
你的存在是因为我
you exist because of me,
但如果他们知道你是怎么放走瑞文的
but you won't if they figure out
你就不会在这里了
how you freed raven.
我们只在瑞文和妈妈
we emp'd the chip
身上植入了芯片  我身上没有
but only in raven and mom, not me.
如果我是你  从某种程度上  我确实是
if i were you-- and, in a way, i am--
我会好好保护这些记忆的
i'd keep this memory safe.
谢谢你  但我要提醒你
thank you, but for the record,
你试图偷走
you tried to steal
你所保存的所有记忆
all those memories you're now saving.
我试着不让你为自己的存在
i tried to spare you the pain and horror
而感到痛苦和恐惧
of your existence.
快乐总是伴随着痛苦
there is not joy without pain.
我从来都不了解人类
i never did understand humans.
那些痛苦的记忆甚至都不在这里
those painful memories aren't even here.
在你的内心深处  你抛弃了它们
they're cast away deep in your mind,
所以你就不用面对它们了
where you don't have to face them,
然而
and yet...
你却无法放手
you can't let them go.
等等  你说这是我的
wait. you said this is a repository
- 记忆库  - 是的
- of my memories... - yes.
但有些东西我从来没有见过
but there's something there i've never seen.
- 圣地是我的  - 撞击警告
- sanctum is mine! - collision alert.
克拉克·格里芬  很高兴见到你
clarke griffin. it's nice to meet you.
我听说过很多你的事
i've heard so many things,
大部分都是谋杀事迹  但是
most of them murdery, but, you know,
没有嘲讽的意思
no judgment.
- 约瑟芬  - 是我本人
- josephine? - in the flesh,
但你不应该打开那扇门的
but you shouldn't have opened that door.
这具身体不够大  容不下我们两个人
this body is not big enough for both of us.
拉塞尔真的这么做了  他偷走了我的身体
russell really did it. he stole my body.
显然他把这里搞砸了
and clearly made a mess of it.
记忆消除失败已经过去几百年了
it's been hundreds of years since a mind wipe failed,
但不得不说  看起来还不错
but i got to say, this isn't bad,
当然了  没有我的思维空间那么有条理
not as organized as my mindspace, of course,
但总体来说还是挺不错的
but mildly impressive.
思维空间
mindspace?
当两个思维共用一个身体时
the brain creates these constructs
大脑就会产生这种结构
when two minds share a body,
就像清醒的梦一样  但没那么有趣
like lucid dreaming only not as fun.
这是一种自我保护机制  把两种
it's a self-preservation thing, trying to keep
思维分开  这样身体就不会死去
the minds separate so the body doesn't die.
但当你打开那扇门时把这一切搞砸了
you kind of messed that up when you opened the door,
所以  因为你
so, you know, thanks
大脑开始加速恶化了
for the accelerated brain deterioration.
等等  你之前经历过这种事吗
wait. you've been through this before?
虽然不像现在这么先进
never anything as advanced as this,
但没错  在加百列
but, yeah, back in the day
完善大脑清除术之前
before gabriel perfected the mind wipe,
发生过这种不幸
there were a few mishaps.
在那些人的思维还存在的时候
i got jacked into some people's minds
我进入了他们的大脑中
while the lights were still on.
- 他们太普通了  - 后来发生了什么事
- they were so average. - what happened?
第一个大脑只有6个月大
the first was a 6-month-old.
她的思维还没有完全形成  里面一片混乱
her mind was unformed, full of chaos,
充满了形状和声音
shapes and sounds.
然后是萨瓦纳
then there was savannah.
我发誓我15岁的时候可没有那么招人讨厌
i swear i was not that obnoxious at 15.
他们都死了
and then they died.
脑出血导致中风
brain hemorrhaging leads to stroke,
我们都倒下了
and we all fall down.
就像母亲分娩一样又脏又疼
it's messy and hurts like a mother,
我不推荐这种做法
would not recommend it.
两个思维  一个大脑  结果总是不大好
two minds, one brain never ends well,
所以这一切  是个大麻烦
so this, it's a problem.
你到底是怎么活下来的
how did you even survive?
你之所以想知道
you just want to know so you
是因为这样你就能摆脱我了
can figure out how to get rid of me.
好吧  你到底听没听我说话
ok. weren't you listening?
如果我们不采取措施的话  这具身体将死去
if we don't do something, this body dies.
- 这就是你希望的吗  - 当然不是
- that what you want? - of course not.
你为什么不能找个新的身体
why can't you just find a new body
把我的还给我
and give mine back?
我可以这样  但这风险很大
i could, i suppose, but it's risky.
上一个铤而走险的普莱姆永远地死去了
the last primes who went on ice died forever.
我可不想要那样的下场
i'm not really into that.
再说了  法律十有八九都是关于占有权的
besides, possession is 9/10 of the law,
说句悄悄话
and, just between us girls,
我还挺喜欢你的身体的
i kind of like your body.
你是个变态
you're a sociopath.
真刻薄  再说了  你也没资格这么说
judgy. besides, like you're one to talk,
死亡指挥官
wanheda.
要我说  你有两个选择
the way i see it, you have two options--
告诉我你是怎么活下来的  然后我可以修好它
tell me how you survived so i can fix it,
我会确保你的人
and i'll make sure your people
从此幸福快乐地生活  或者你不说
like happily ever after or don't,
最终 我们都死掉
and eventually, we'll both die, anyway.
唯一的不同是  我会在某个地方重生
the difference is, i'll be reborn in someone else,
告诉我父亲发生了什么
tell my father what happened,
他会把你的人都赶出去  任他们死在树林里
and he'll kick your people out to die in the woods.
去你妹的
go float yourself.
我完全不懂那是什么意思
i have no idea what that means.
意思是  我们什么都不会告诉你
it means that i'm not telling you anything,
我从不会轻言放弃
and i don't go down easy.
你很自私  还很蠢
you're selfish, not to mention dumb.
你的思维空间储蓄着你所有的记忆
your mindspace contains all your memories,
所以  试着不要在脑海里回想你放他们的地方
so try not to think of where you keep them.
你好
hello.
你可以控制自己的思维空间  克拉克
you control your mindspace, clarke.
可惜你不能控制自己的思想
too bad you can't control your thoughts.
我收回我的称赞  这个地方简直一团乱
i rescind my compliments. this is a disaster.
没人教过你
didn't anyone ever teach you
什么是组织结构吗
about organizational structure?
滚出我的脑袋
get out of my head.
别介啊  克拉克  分享就是关爱
now, now, clarke. sharing is caring.
克拉克  当心
clarke! watch out!
我不会让你死在这场战争里的
i will not let you die in this war.
把儿童虐待说成是保护  可以啊
child abuse dressed up as protection. cool.
- 克拉克  等等  - 真的吗
- clarke, wait. -  really?
你是不是藏了一段记忆  克拉克
are you hiding a memory from me, clarke?
- 没礼貌  - 你永远不会找到的
- rude. - you'll never find it.
你要知道  我研究各种生命体  但是
you know, i study all life, but insects
最让我着迷的是昆虫
always fascinated me most.
它们冷酷无情
they're merciless, ruthless.
我很敬佩这一点
i respect that.
人的感情太混乱了
people are so messy, so emotional.
也因为感情  他们总是暴露自己
because of that, they give themselves away.
我总是可以把他们看得一清二楚
i could always figure people out,
哪怕我还只是个孩子的时候
even as a kid.
我就可以发现  人在紧张的时候
i could tell when they were nervous.
脉搏跳动更快
their pulses would beat faster.
眼神飘忽  呼吸加快
eyes would dart. breath would quicken.
这是生理反应
it's physiological.
你知道我的蜘蛛感应
you know what my spidey senses
现在告诉我什么吗
are telling me about you right now?
我绝对不会帮你清除我的记忆
that i'll never help you wipe my mind?
你自以为自己很厉害
you think you're a badass,
不过是为了掩盖自我怀疑而虚张声势
but your bravado covers self-doubt.
你必须把你的秘密具象化
you had to physicalize your secret
这样你才可以就近掌控它
so you could keep it close, where you have control.
我打赌它现在就在你的身上
i bet you have it on you right now.
让我拿走吧
now let me have it.
警告  撞击警告
warning. collision alert.
我们回来了 小贱人
we're back, bitches.
- 怎么可能  - 拜托
- how? - come on.
你还没反应过来吗
you're smarter than that.
你以为我们是怎么复活的
how do you think we're resurrected?
我的思维会重启我的意识
my mind drive backs up my consciousness.
我在思维空间里是不会死的
i can't die in the mindspace,
但你会  除非是你藏起来的东西
but you can unless whatever fluke
可以把你带回来
kept you here can bring you back.
我的朋友  可要坚持下去哦
you, my friend, are playing for keeps.
大约一个小时之前  我打了一剂镇静剂
i took a sedative about an hour ago,
所以我有一整晚的时间
so that gives me all night
在这里杀了你  或者找到
to kill you in here or find the memory
如何在外面杀死你的那段记忆
of how i can kill you out there.
你喜欢哪种
got a preference?
简单还是困难模式  克拉克  无论如何  你死定了
easy or hard way, clarke, either way, you die.
你在这里干什么
what are you doing here?
我必须先她一步
i just have to stay ahead of her.
- 如果我可以躲起来  - 你很擅长躲嘛
- if i can hide-- - you're good at that,
别人战斗的时候  你就躲起来
aren't you, hiding while other people fight.
什么
what?
你在决议会的时候就躲起来了
you did that during the conclave.
而我却在外面为所有人的生命战斗
while i was up there fighting for everyone's lives,
你在这里窃取我流血得来的东西
you were down here stealing what i bled for.
不管了  好吧  我们之前一笔勾销了
whatever. fine. you wrote me off,
十分隐秘的决议会  我懂
the conclave at tondc--i get it--
但问题是  我真心以为
but the thing is, i really thought
你是在乎贝拉米的
you cared about bellamy.
你们两个我都在乎
i care about both of you.
但你把他留在那里等死
but you left him in the pits to die, anyway.
我别无选择  他理解的
i had to, and he understands.
他原谅了我
he forgave me.
是吗
did he?
那为什么他不在这段记忆里
then why isn't he here in this memory?
我告诉你为什么
i'll tell you why.
因为你不敢面对他
because you're too afraid to face him
因为你知道他认为你是一个怪物
because you know he thinks you're a monster
可以抛弃任何人
who will abandon anyone.
我不是那样的人
that is not who i am.
我不知道你为什么要和我争辩  克拉克
i don't know why you're arguing with me, clarke.
毕竟  我只是
after all, i'm just
你潜意识的投射
a subconscious projection of you.
警告  撞击警告
warning. collision alert.
- 帮帮我  - 你觉得可能吗
- help me. - that'll happen.
哈哈  你看起来很搞笑
ha ha! you look fun.
你上吧
have at her.
即使是你自己的意识投射都讨厌你  克拉克
even your projections hate you, clarke.
玛雅
maya?
你好  克拉克
hi, clarke.
不  我不想这样  我不想的
no. i don't want this. i don't want any of this.
问题是  克拉克
that's the thing, clarke.
你心中的一部分  确实想要这样
some part of you does want this,
否则  我不会在这里
or i wouldn't be here.
我有个问题要问你
i have a question of you.
你为什么要为了活下去拼命挣扎
why are you fighting so hard to stay alive?
- 我必须  - 拯救你的族人  我知道
- i have to-- - save your people. yes. i know.
可惜我不是你的族人
too bad i wasn't in that group, huh?
我没想过要伤害你  玛雅
i never meant to hurt you, maya.
对不起
i'm sorry.
你不停地道歉
you keep saying that.
告诉我  你是不是也觉得对不起贾斯珀
tell me, are you sorry about jasper, too?
毕竟  我的死是送他
after all, killing me is what sent him
进入深渊的原因
off the deep end.
- 那是贾斯珀自己的选择  - 不对
- jasper made his choice. - wrong.
他的死也是你造成的
his death is on you, too.
别人总是为你做的事情付出代价
you do things, but other people pay the price.
好了  够了
ok. that's enough.
你害死的人比你救的更多
you've killed more people than you've saved.
你知道吗
do you realize that?
如果你真的想要
if you actually cared
拯救别人
about saving people's lives,
最好还是走开
you'd walk away.
你知道我是怎么想的吗
you know what i think?
你喜欢做救世主的感觉
you like being the savior.
你喜欢扮演上帝
you like playing god.
你和普莱姆没什么不同
you're not so different from the primes, you know.
辐射警告
radiation alert.
她要来了
she's coming.
你为什么不直接放弃
why don't you just give in to her?
就这一次  放弃控制权
just give up control for once.
控制
control.
是我在控制
i'm in control. huh.
我有主意了
i have an idea.
你脸上有东西
you have a little something--
她把东西藏在了山洞里
she hid it in the cave.
有没有搞错
are you kidding me?
你的意识投射真是神助攻
i mean, your projections are the best.
要不要带我们去
care to take us?
谢谢你  化脓女
thank you, melty girl.
不错的停靠位置
nice parking spot.
抓到你了
gotcha.
你不能控制这里  这里是我的思维空间
you have no control here. this is my mindspace.
原来  我想创造什么都可以
turns out, i can create whatever i want,
包括她
including her.
很可爱
cute.
别白费力气了
i wouldn't bother.
项圈已经标记了山洞的位置
the collar is geotagged to the cave.
好吧  所以你的计划是什么  拖延到我醒来
ok. what's your plan here, stall until i wake up?
我会在一个又一个夜晚不停地尝试
i'll just try again night after night,
我在这里的时间越多
and the more time i spend here,
你就死得越快  让我告诉你
the faster you die, and let me tell you,
死亡可不是有趣可爱的东西
that death ain't fun or pretty.
你赢不了的  白费力气干什么
you can't win, so why bother?
确保你不会得逞
to make sure you lose.
我  我会找到活下去的方式
me, i'll find a way to survive.
我总是能活下去
i always do.
勇气可嘉
you got spunk. i'll give you that.
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
要是情况不同  我们可以成为朋友的
things were different, we could have been friends,
但我现在很无聊
but i'm bored now.
嘿  克拉克  我或许不能
hey, clarke, i may not be able
在你的思维空间创造任何东西
to create anything in your mindspace,
但我绝对可以带东西进来
but i can sure bring something in.
我们分头行动  别浪费时间了
let's split up and stop playing games.
你不是在玩猫捉老鼠的游戏
you're not a cat toying with a mouse.
她很危险  杀了她
she's dangerous. kill her.
学过动物学入门吗  克拉克
ever take zoology 101, clarke--
捕食者的捕猎策略
hunting tactics of predator species?
没有嘛  那我快速教你一下
no? how about a quick lesson, then?
- 最常见的  - 捕猎者会
- the most common... - ...pursuit predators
消耗能量追捕速度较慢的猎物
expend energy running down slower prey,
或者保持匀速  让目标精疲力尽
or they pace themselves and let their prey tire out.
我提议第三种方案
i'm proposing a third option--
告诉我你把东西藏在了哪里
just show me where you hid it
这样省的咱俩都累得慌了
so we can both kick back and rest.
这么跑来跑去真是很幼稚
all this running is plain undignified.
你为什么要逃避呢
why did you avoid this?
玩蛋去吧你
"go float yourself."
你的动物学入门学得不错啊  克拉克
a-plus zoology 101, clarke.
你这种注意力干扰策略还不错
that was very effective distraction display,
但我更聪明
but i know better.
快艇骰子
yahtzee.
我猜猜
let me guess.
离远点
get away from that.
你会没事的
you're gonna be ok.
克拉克啊
oh, hey, clarke.
这就是你一直极力避免的地方吗
this is the place you were avoiding?
也没那么吓人好吧
it's not even that scary.
有一点儿不吉利
huh. it's a little ominous.
你不应该来的
you shouldn't be here.
躲在这里很聪明啊
it was clever hiding it here,
最危险的地方就是最安全的地方
the place you wouldn't go
你知道我不会来这里找的
so the place i wouldn't look.
但记忆是很有趣的  知道吧
memory is funny, you know?
那些格式化的东西  那些创伤
the formative stuff-- the traumas,
那些我们无法躲避  无法忘记的东西
the things we can't move past--
深深地埋藏在我们的脑干之中
they live deep in the brain stem.
这是花钱找心理医生也没办法修复的创伤
these are the wounds we pay shrinks not to fix.
这种地方控制着我们
these places control us,
让我们变成了我们
make us who we are.
它实际上与大脑较低的功能有关
it's actually connected to the lower brain function--
呼吸  条件反射
breathing, reflexes.
所以你想到莱克萨的时候会哭
it's why you cry when you think of lexa.
闭嘴
shut up.
你为那些因你而死的人内疚
all of this is guilt for the deaths you've caused,
但我不理解
but i don't get it.
你为什么会如此遍体鳞伤呢
why are you so torn up?
你所做的一切  都是为了救你的人民
everything you did was to save your people.
- 换我我也会这样的  - 这是一种认可
- i'd do the same thing. - a ringing endorsement.
但我不明白的是  为什么你现在
the thing i don't get is why you don't care
不再在乎拯救他们了呢
about saving your people now.
什么
what?
好比说你能想办法打过我
let's say you could somehow fight me off
拿回你的身体
and get your body back.
你觉得这对你的家人和朋友会如何呢
what would that do to your friends and family?
你觉得我父亲会这么轻易让我走吗
do you think my father would just let me go?
你现在所做的一切
what you're doing right now
会造成你们的种族灭绝
leads to the genocide of your people,
当然我觉得这对你来说是很正常的
which, i guess, is par for the course with you.
- 我只是想活下去  - 真的吗
- i just want to live. - do you, though?
你的思想好像不是这么想的
because your mind sure doesn't seem to.
你有没有想过  解决办法
have you ever even once considered that
可能是牺牲你自己呢
the solution is to sacrifice yourself?
你的人民很安全  贝拉米确认过了
your people are safe. bellamy made sure of it.
虽然他不能接受你的死亡
i mean, he took your death hard, sure,
但他了解一个领袖想要维护和平
but he knew the only thing a leader could do
唯一能做的事情
was to strike a deal for peace.
现在该你挺身而出了
now it's time for you to step up.
优雅的鞠躬退场  你的人民
bow out gracefully, and your people
从此会幸福地生活下去
get to live happily ever after.
你骗人
you're lying.
贝拉米绝对不会做这种交易的
bellamy would never make a deal like that.
你这么不信任我  我很难过啊  克拉克
the lack of trust hurts me, clarke,
所有我带了这个
so that's why i brought this.
你有图案  我有书  谁也别说谁
you have drawings. i have books. don't judge.
给你  拿着
here. take it.
这不是骗你的  我不这么玩儿
it's not a trick. i don't play that way.
我能保证你们剩下的人的安全
i can guarantee safety for the rest of your people.
我们会在这个星球上一起
we'll share everything we've learned
分享我们所学到的存活技能
about surviving on this moon.
我接受这个交易  因为这是聪明的举动
i'll take your deal because it's the smart play
也是她会做出来的
and it's the move she would have made.
该是时候  你为你的人民
it's time for you to sacrifice
牺牲了  克拉克
for your people, clarke.
不要再开启一场  他们需要参与的战争
don't start another war they'll have to fight.
我需要他们安全
i need them to be ok.
我跟你保证  你的人会安全的
by my word, your people will be safe.
明天早上  贝拉米第一件事
bellamy is meeting with my father
就是去见我父亲
first thing in the morning
商讨给他们建造一个住所的事情
to discuss building them a compound.
他们会有新家  新的生活
they'll have a new home, a new life.
麦蒂也能跟其他孩子一样上学了
madi can go to school just like any other kid.
你的朋友们也能安定下来了
your friends can settle down.
所有人  包括你  都不用再战斗了
everyone can stop fighting, including you.
告诉麦蒂我爱她
tell madi i love her...
也告诉所有人
and tell all of them.
你不用管贝拉米和瑞文了
you forgot bellamy and raven.
高级环境工程师
senior environmental engineer,
副资源官
deputy resource officer.
这意味着由我来掌控这些机器
that means i'm in charge of the machines
保证我们的水可以喝
that keep our water safe to drink
食物可以被安全食用
and our food safe to eat.
电磁脉冲
an emp.
不错
cool.
很快就会结束的
it'll be over soon....
我保证
i promise.
爸爸
dad?
蒙蒂
oh, monty...
你觉得这就是更好了吗
you call this doing better?
放弃不叫更好
giving up isn't better.
我不是
that's not what i'm--
我这样做是为了其他人
i'm doing this for the others.
- 他们会活下去的  - 都是为了我的人民吗
- they'll live. - "it's all for my people"?
这种话我听过了  克拉克
look. i've heard that before, clarke.
只不过是借口
it's just an excuse.
是你告诉我  我不是神的
you're the one who told me i'm not god,
我不能决定谁生谁死
that i don't get to decide who lives or dies.
你现在如愿了
well, you got your wish.
我不再为别人做决定了
i'm not deciding for anyone else...
只为我
just for me.
是这样
look.
我能理解  无止无休的
i get it. it's been endless.
去忍受  为了我们可以不用这样
bearing it so we don't have to,
换做是谁都会累的
anyone would be tired...
但你真的要抛下她吗
but are you really gonna leave her?
她没了我会更好
she's better off without me.
我觉得不是的
i don't think that's true.
我妈妈会照顾她的
my mom will take care of her,
而贝拉米已经答应了条件
and bellamy already made a deal
让大家都安全
that keeps them all safe.
关键是在于做好人啊
this is about being the good guys. yeah.
这个交易能让我们的人活下去
that deal means our side gets to live,
但代价呢
but at what cost?
你是让这些杀了人类的人
you're giving in to people who
得以永生啊
murder human beings to live forever.
说起来容易  但是在真实世界中
that's easy to say, but in the real world,
我们得为自己的人民做最好的考虑啊
we have to do what's best for our people.
做错事绝对不是最好的考虑啊
doing the wrong thing is never what's best.
为达目的不择手段啊
the ends don't justify the means.
你知道的
you know that.
你想让我怎么样  蒙蒂
what do you want from me, monty?
已经太晚了
it's too late.
约瑟芬已经拿到记忆了
josephine already has the memory.
一旦她醒过来
as soon as she wakes up,
她会知道怎么把我从我的脑海中弄出去的
she'll know how to get me out of my head.
都结束了
it's over.
我们走着瞧吧
we'll see about that.
这是约瑟芬的思维空间
this is josephine's mindspace.
由她控制的
she controls it.
她能怎么办  杀了你吗
what she gonna do, kill you?
230年的记忆
230 years of memories.
好消息是
good news is,
我们可以在这里影响她的身体
we can affect her body in here.
但坏消息是
bad news is,
约瑟芬好像可以感觉到
josephine seems to sense it.
来  看看有什么可以利用的
come on. let's find something we can use.
这都是按照时间顺序排列的
they're all in chronological order.
我还是更喜欢你的绘画
i like your drawings better.
你看
look.
这一定是她保存原始伤口的地方
this must be where she keeps her primal wounds.
她说这会产生身体反应的
she said they create a physical response.
我们可以从那里控制我的身体
we could control my body from there.
好的  要花一点时间
on it. this'll take a minute.
我打开的时候  你去看看她是谁
find out who she is while i get this open.
再来一次
one more time.
婆  罗  洲
b-o-r-n-e-o.
你要承认啊  约瑟芬
you can admit it, josephine.
你有一种执念
you have a fixation.
这叫做感谢
it's called appreciation.
你不怀念你最初的身体吗
don't you miss your first body?
我只想活在当下
i'm all about living in the now,
关心这里的人
focusing on the people that are here,
而不是那些化为灰烬的人
not those faded into dust.
或许是时候
maybe it's time for you to refocus
重新关注自己的族人
on your own kind.
有些人可不值得
some of these people aren't worth
你的关注  莉莉
your attention, lee-lee.
我能说什么呢  我思想开明
well, what can i say? i am open-minded.
今晚这杯果汁真是让我有点晕
this jo juice is really getting me tonight.
是吗
is it? hmm.
这不只是果汁
this isn't just j-juice.
是睡眠浆果吗
shuimian jiangguo?
你分类过它们  我还以为适合你呢
i thought it was fitting, given you cataloged them,
我以为你还有
though i still think that you could've beat
睡眠屏障
"sleeping berries."
为什么
tell me why.
你一定要理解  莉莉
you have to understand, lee-lee,
埃萨克是个威胁
isaac was a threat.
他从来不会伤害任何人  他是我的
he'd never hurt anyone, and he was mine.
怎么  你见不得我高兴吗
what, you couldn't stand to see me happy?
他违抗普莱姆家族的意志
he defied the will of the primes.
他蔑视祭品
he defied oblation.
那不是普莱姆家族的意志
that's not the will of the primes.
那是你的意志
that's just you.
过去20年间只诞生了两位主人
only two hosts have been born in the past 20 years.
零的血统已不纯正
the nulls are muddying the bloodline.
没有祭品  我们将走向灭绝
without oblation, we go extinct.
在你决定和埃萨克发生关系之前
hell, you helped me spread the word
你帮我传出了消息
before you decided to hop in the sack with isaac.
现在你口气和赖克一样
now you're sounding like riker.
人们不仅是自身的血脉
people are more than their blood.
我现在说的是更大的构想
i'm talking about the bigger picture here.
你的回答是谋杀吗
your answer is murder?
你以为我没注意到吗
did you think i wouldn't notice?
我不知道你是怎么了
i don't know what happened to you,
但你不该是这样
but this is not who you are.
我厌倦了  你为何给我下药啊
i'm getting bored. why the hell did you drug me?
这样他们就相信这是意外了
so they believe this was an accident.
放开我
let go of me. uh!
约瑟芬·艾达· 莱特本恩七世
你肯定十分不在意我  埃萨克
you must think very little of me, isaac.
你以为我没注意到
did you think i wouldn't notice
我的祭品都不见了吗
my offering was going missing?
森林不会喂养地这么快
the forest doesn't feed that quickly.
你是把他们交给加百列了吗
are you giving them to gabriel?
约瑟芬  我可以解释
josephine, i can explain.
我懂了
oh, i get it.
你以为自己是凯莉的宠儿
you think because you're kaylee's pet,
就得意忘形了
you're more than what you are.
我是啊  我们都是
i am. we all are.
我们无法承受宿主
just because we can't bear a host
不意味着我们就没有价值
doesn't mean we're worthless.
我同意
i agree.
真的吗
really?
没有价值意味着中立
worthless implies a sort of neutrality,
中立没有积极价值
something with no positive value,
但零  你不仅是无用
but nulls, you are less than useless.
你还玷污了血统
you dilute the bloodline.
你让任何人
you make it less likely
都没法承受宿主了
that anyone would bear a host.
我不能让这种事发生
i can't let that happen.
我必须考虑我的族人
i have to think of my people.
我们就是你的族人
we are your people.
我们能有一番大作为
we could be so much more.
我们能做很多事  只要允许我们
we could do so much more, if only we were allowed
真正的活着  只要你让我们
to truly live, if you would let us
不仅仅当你的警卫
be more than just your janitors or guards.
如果你没有给敌人派送兵力
that argument would carry a lot more weight
这话还有点分量
if you weren't delivering soldiers to our enemies.
告诉我  加百利如何了
tell me, how is gabriel?
他最后的宿主现在也有95岁了吧
his latest host must be 95 by now.
我是在尽量让自己的族人活着
i'm just trying to keep our people alive.
祭品是不对的
oblation is wrong.
为何要牺牲这个孩子
why should this child be sacrificed?
他什么都没
he's done noth
别担心  埃萨克
don't worry, isaac.
你的精神会永存的
your spirit shall live eternal.
你说得对  我们不能让她赢
you were right. we can't let her win.
就差一点了
almost got it.
好了
yes!
* god rest ye, merry gentlemen *
* let nothing you dismay *
* remember, christ our savior... *
被炸毁前的地球
earth before the bombs.
嘿  快看啊
hey, check it out.
让她接受世纪审判
好地方
nice place.
她为什么把这段记忆封存起来了
why would she keep this memory locked away?
更重要的是
more importantly,
我们怎么控制这里
how do we get control from here?
弗兰克文件
过来
come on.
我发誓   我下学期要选汉伦的课
ugh, i swear, i'm taking hanlen next semester.
我再也不想对付西尔维斯特了
i can't deal with silvestri anymore.
你是说你再也不参加
does that mean you're not going
机密的小家庭项目了吗
on your little, secret family project?
我告诉他们别选了
i told them no.
如果你选了汉伦
well, if your signing up for hanlen,
就穿超短裙去
pull out your miniskirts.
他能看那些喜欢的女孩看到硬
he gives a half-grade bump to girls he likes to look at.
嘿
hey.
我在供水抗议会上
i was looking for you
找你来着
at the water rationing protest,
我以为你想参加呢
thought you posted something about going.
人太多了
too many people, you know.
外面尘土飞扬的
and it's really dusty outside.
是啊
yeah. sure.
我问了  如果你想去的话
uh, i asked, and there's plenty of room
比较语言学课
at the comparative linguistics thing
有很多空位
if you want to go.
我说不好
i don't know.
我最近不太愿意交际
i'm not really feeling that social lately.
你还是觉得我配不上你  是吗
you still think you're too good for me, huh?
- 我不是那个意思  - 别骗人了
- that's not what i-- - don't lie.
承认吧
just admit it.
别再戏弄我了  你就承认了吧
stop toying with me and just admit what you are.
我不是
i--i don't--
我试过了  打电话  发短信
i mean, i tried-- calls, texts,
处处为你着想
you know, being thoughtful.
我得到了什么呢
what do i get?
你无动于衷
nothing.
你要干嘛
what are you doing?
你给我闭上嘴
thinking you should shut the hell up.
我明白你的意思了  你个贱人
message received, you stuck-up bitch.
你不想见我
you don't want to see me.
那就看这个吧
you can see this.
咱们赶紧离开这里
let's get out of here!
这是她无法面对的事情
this is the thing she couldn't face.
怪不得她改变了离开计划
no wonder she changed her mind about leaving.
我们需要用它来控制你的身体
we need to use it to control your body.
我有办法了
i have an idea.
警报  炸弹袭击
alert. incoming bombshells.
立刻找掩护
take cover immediately.
快点  躲起来
quick, hide.
你就不该来这儿
you never should have come here!
滚开
get out!
我给了你机会  安静地离开这里
aah! i gave you the chance to go quietly.
我说过  我要帮助你的族人
i said i'd help your people.
交易结束了
deal's off.
她醒了
she's awake.
我赢了
i win.
好了
all right.
作为无视你谋杀克拉克的交换
in exchange for ignoring that you murdered clarke...
你要与我们联合
you build us a compound.
那些母亲和孩子们呢  他们会同意吗
what about the mother and child? will they agree?
我来搞定我的族人
i'll handle our people.
建立住所需要多久
how long will it take to build?
等一会儿  亲爱的
just a moment, sweetheart.
有我们所有人的帮助
with all of our people helping you,
一定会很快的
it will go much faster.
和赖克聊一下工作行程
talk to riker about a work schedule,
你需要50个族人出份详细的计划
and you'll need a detail of about 50 of your own people.
要建一座墙
you'll build a wall that--
贝拉米
bellamy.
贝拉米  你同意吗
bellamy, are we agreed?
同意
yeah.
我们都同意
we're good for now.
我会命令开始建造住所
i'll order construction to begin.
走吧
let's go.
乔茜
josie...
变身出了什么问题吗
did something go wrong with the transfer?
算是吧
you could say that.
她还在我的脑海里  但别担心
she's still in my head, but don't worry.
我知道如何把她赶尽杀绝
i know how to kill her once and for all.
还记得派克教咱的摩斯密码吗
hey, remember when pike taught us morse code?
地球杀戮的时候我几乎都沉睡着  所以
i slept through most of earth skills, so--
好吧  约瑟芬刚刚在胳膊上
ok. josephine was tapping out morse code
敲了摩斯密码
on her arm.
还
活
着
这是什么意思
what does it mean?
意思是克拉克还活着  我们要把她弄回来
it means clarke's alive, and we're gonna get her back.
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177